Tala Touckley

FILMMAKER + PHOTOGRAPHER

+971586880688 talatouckley@gmail.com Dubai, UAE. talatouckley.com

EDUCATION

B.S Multimedia Design American University of Sharjah 2016-2020

SKILLS

Communicative
Team player
Cooperative
Hardworking
Energetic
Flexible

EXHIBITIONS

Noon Awards, Sharjah Ladies Club Desolate photograph | March 2021

Vantage Point Sharjah 8,

Sharjah Art Foundation Desolate, Casement, & Pathless photographs | May 2020

Six Degrees Online Exhibition, Wasl project | April 2019 - October 2019

Bait Al Naboodah Museum

Maknoon Exhibition: Music of the Sea project | April 2019

- October 2019

SOFTWARES

Premiere Pro Final Cut Pro Aftereffects Photoshop InDesign

LANGUAGES

Arabic English

PROFILE

As a highly motivated Arab female filmmaker, I am passionate about all aspects of filmmaking, particularly directing & editing. Over the past four years, I have displayed my experimental photography & short films across the Arab region. My short film, The Vase, was selected for the Cannes Short Film Corner, France. Moving forward, my goal is to delve into on-set production & hone my skills in that aspect of filmmaking.

EXPERIENCE

Video Editor | April 2022 - present

KERNING CULTURES

- Managing structure, visual, and video components for 3+ shows.
- Strategizing video content across all social media platforms.
- Conducting network-wide "DIY Filmmaking: Your Environment Is All You Need" to demonstrate the best practices for self recording.
- Creating a database for BRoll to increase efficiency.
- Contributing to Arab Podcasts within the region by animating and editing promotional social media videos.

Content Creator | April 2022 - November 2022 TAMARA

- Directed, produced & edited Ramadan campaign video to build brand awareness & conserve business relationship.
- Ideated & created 50+ social media posts in order to increase engagement and brand awareness.
- Creating digital ads & announcement posts to advertise large merchants such as The Giving Movement, Next, Guess & more.
- Communicating with multiple stakeholders across different departments to create content.
- Creating social media strategies for in-store content & built a guideline.

Multimedia Specialist | February 2021 - April 2022

AMERICAN UNIVERSITY OF SHARJAH

- Directing multiple live streaming events with adequate video lighting & sound on sets.
- Managing the entire film production process for 30+ projects, from brainstorming to filming to editing.
- Conducting 20+ interviews to share stories amongst campus life.
- Conceptualizing & overseeing the creation of multiple motion graphics projects.
- Collecting BRoll & event coverage for 10+ events.